（维吉尼亚州匡蒂科附近森林）
《沉默的羔羊》
史达琳！
Starling!
克劳福要见你
Crawford wants to see you in his office.
谢谢
Thank you, sir.
（伤害）
（苦难）
（痛苦）
（喜欢它）
-克丽丝　-你好
- Clarice. - Hey.
（行为科学组）
找克劳福吗？
Looking for Crawford?
他快回来了，在他的办公室等一会吧
He should be back soon. Why don't you wait in his office?
（比尔剥下第五个人的皮）
史达琳
Starling.
-克丽丝，早安　-早安，克劳福先生
- Clarice M. Good morning. - Morning, Mr. Crawford.
抱歉突然把你召离课堂
Sorry to pull you off the course at such short notice.
你的导师说你是班里的高材生
Your instructors say you're in the top quarter of your class.
希望是吧，他们还没有公布成绩
I hope so. They haven't posted any grades yet.
有一个任务要办，于是我想起你
A job's come up, and I thought about you.
这不是正式的任务，较像一份有趣的差事
Not a job, really, more of an interesting errand.
坐下
Sit down.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我记得你出席过，我在维吉尼亚大学的讲座
I remember you from my seminar at UVA.
你追问我本局在胡佛年代的，公民权益记录
You grilled me on the bureau's civil rights record in the Hoover years.
我给了你甲等
I gave you an A.
是甲下
A minus, sir.
双主修，心理学及犯罪学，以优异成绩毕业
Double major, psych and criminology, graduated magna.
在瑞辛格疗养院做过夏季实习
Summer internships at the Reitzinger Clinic.
它说你毕业后，想在行为科学组替我工作
It says when you graduate you want to work for me in Behavioral Science.
是的，我很想
Yes, very much, sir. Very much.
我们正在访问被囚禁的连环杀手
We're interviewing all serial killers in custody...
作变态行为的分析
for a psycho-behavioral profile.
对一些悬案会有很大帮助
It could be a real help in unsolved cases.
他们大都乐意跟我们谈
Most of them have been happy to talk to us.
你会否很易受惊的？
Do you spook easily, Starling?
不会
Not yet, sir.
我们最想见的那个人拒绝合作
The one we want most refuses to help.
我想你去精神病院找他
I want you to go after him in the asylum.
那个人是谁？
Who's the subject?
-心理医生汉尼拔・莱达　-食人狂魔汉尼拔
- The psychiatrist, Hannibal Lecter. - "Hannibal the Cannibal."
我想他不会跟你交谈
I don't expect him to talk to you...
但无论如何我们都得尝试
but I have to be able to say we tried.
若他不合作，我要如实报告
If he won't cooperate, I want straight reporting.
他的容貌和监狱里的状况如何？
How's he look? How's his cell?
他有没有素描，绘画？如果有，他都画些什么？
Is he sketching, drawing? If he is, what's he sketching?
这是莱达的档案...
Here's a dossier on Lecter...
问卷副本和你的身份证
copy of our questionnaire and an I.D. for you.
周三早上八点把你的报告交给我
Have your memo on my desk by 0800, Wednesday.
好的
Okay.
对不起，为什么这样急？
Excuse me, sir, but why the urgency?
莱达已经坐牢很多年了
Lecter's been in prison for years.
他和水牛比尔是否有关连？
Is there some connection between him and Buffalo Bill?
但愿有，我要你非常留意
I wish there were. Now, I want your full attention, Starling.
-知道　-要非常小心应付汉尼拔・莱达
- Yes, sir. - Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter.
精神病院的奇顿医生，会给你讲解接见程序
Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over all the physical procedures used.
无论如何不可偏离程序
Do not deviate from them for any reason whatsoever.
你不可向他透露私人事情
You're to tell him nothing personal.
你不想汉尼拔・莱达知道你的思想的
You don't want Hannibal Lecter inside your head.
执行你的任务，但千万别忘记他的身份
Just do your job but never forget what he is.
是什么？
And what is that?
他是个魔头，一个变态狂人
Oh, he's a monster, a pure psychopath.
可以生擒一个已很难得了
It's so rare to capture one alive.
从研究角度来说，莱达是我们最有价值的资产
From a research point of view, Lecter is our most prized asset.
我们有很多探员来这里的
We get a lot of detectives here...
但我记不起有这样漂亮的一个
but I must say I can't remember one as attractive.
你会在巴尔的摩过夜吗？
Will you be in Baltimore overnight?
如果你有适当的向导，这可以是个很好玩的城市
Because this can be quite a fun town if you have the right guide.
我肯定这是个了不起的城市
I'm sure this is a great town, Dr. Chilton...
但我要见莱达医生，下午还要回去报告
but I must talk to Dr. Lecter and report back this afternoon.
是的，那么我们快点吧
I see. Well, let's make this quick, then.
我们尝试研究他，但他太高深了，一般的测试都不适用
We've tried to study him, but he's too sophisticated for the standard tests.
他很讨厌我们的
Oh, my, does he hate us.
他觉得我是他的报应
He thinks I'm his nemesis.
克劳福真是聪明，他利用你
Crawford's very clever, isn't he, using you?
-什么意思？　-找个漂亮的女郎来引诱他
- What do you mean, sir? - Pretty young woman to turn him on.
我相信这八年来莱达都没见过女人，而你正合他的胃口
I don't believe Lecter's seen a woman in eight years, and you are his taste.
恕我直言
So to speak.
我毕业于维吉尼亚大学，它不是一间仪态学校
I graduated from UVA. It's not a charm school.
很好，你该能记着那些规矩了
Good. Then you should be able to remember the rules.
不要触摸或接近那块玻璃，只可传递柔软的纸张给他
Do not touch or approach the glass. Pass him nothing but soft paper.
不可有铅笔或原子笔，纸张上不可有钉书钉或夹子
No pencils or pens, no staples or paper clips in his paper.
只可用那个活动食物架传送
Use the sliding food carrier, no exceptions.
不可接受他给你的东西
If he passes you anything, do not accept.
-明白吗？　-明白
- Do you understand? - Yes, I understand, sir.
我让你看看，为何我们要有这些戒备
I'm going to show you why we insist on such precautions.
在1981年7月8日的下午
On the afternoon of July 8, 1981...
他说胸口痛，被带往医疗室
he complained of chest pains and was taken to the dispensary.
为方便做心电图，他的口罩被除下
His mouthpiece was removed for an EKG.
当护士靠近他身边时，他对她做了这个
When the nurse leaned over him, he did this to her.
医生们算是重整了她的下颚，救回她一只眼睛
The doctors managed to reset her jaw, more or less. Save one of her eyes.
即使在他吃她的舌头时，他的脉搏从没超过85
His pulse never got above 85, even when he ate her tongue.
-我把他关在这里　-奇顿医生
- I keep him in here. - Dr. Chilton.
若莱达觉得你是他的敌人，那么...
If Lecter feels that you're his enemy, then...
若我单独去的话，我们运气可能会好一点
Maybe we'll have more luck if I go by myself.
你认为如何？
What do you think?
你若在我办公室时提出来，就可省掉我的时间了
You might have suggested this in my office and saved me the time.
是的，但我会错过了和你同行的乐趣
Yes, sir, but then I would have missed the pleasure of your company, sir.
她完事后带她出去吧
When she's finished, bring her out.
你好，我是巴尼，他说过了，不要走近那块玻璃
Hi, I'm Barney. He told you, don't get near the glass?
对，他说过了，我是克丽丝・史达琳
Yes, he did. Clarice Starling.
幸会，你可以把大衣挂在那里
Nice to meet you. You can hang your coat there if you like.
好的，谢谢你
Okay. Thank you, I will.
他在最尽头的那个牢房
He's past the others. The last cell.
靠右走吧
You keep to the right.
-我放了一张椅子给你　-很好，谢谢你
- I put out a chair for you. - Yes, that's very good, thank you.
我会看着，你不会有事的
I'll be watching. You'll do fine.
我可以闻到你的私处
I can smell your cunt.
早安
Good morning.
莱达医生，我叫克丽丝・史达琳，可否跟你谈一会？
Dr. Lecter, my name is Clarice Starling. May I speak with you?
你是克劳福的人，是吗？
You're one of Jack Crawford's, aren't you?
是的
I am, yes.
可否看看你的证件？
May I see your credentials?
当然可以
Certainly.
靠近一点，劳烦你
Closer, please.
近一点
Closer.
一周内后就到期了，你不是真的联邦调查局探员吧
That expires in one week. You're not real FBI, are you?
我仍在受训
I'm still in training at the academy.
-克劳福派个见习生来见我？　-是的，我是个学生
- Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me? - Yes, I'm a student.
我是来向你学习的
I'm here to learn from you.
也许你可以决定，我是否够资格这样做
Maybe you can decide if I'm qualified enough to do that.
你很不老实呢，史达琳探员
That is rather slippery of you, Agent Starling.
请坐
Sit. Please.
告诉我，迈克斯对你说了什么？
Now then, tell me. What did Miggs say to you?
隔壁的“多面人迈克斯”
"Multiple Miggs" in the next cell.
他向你发出嘶嘶声，他说了些什么？
He hissed at you. What did he say?
他说“我可以闻到你的私处”
He said, "I can smell your cunt."
是吧
I see.
我可闻不到
I myself cannot.
你用爱肤恩润肤膏
You use Evyan skin cream.
有时你会涂点香水
And sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps.
但今天没有
But not today.
这些画是你画的吗？
Did you do all these drawings?
那是从观景楼远望的大教堂
That is the Duomo, seen from the Belvedere.
你知道佛罗伦斯吗？
Do you know Florence?
那些细节都是来自记忆的吗？
All that detail just from memory, sir?
史达琳探员，我只有记忆，没有景观
Memory, Agent Starling, is what I have instead of a view.
你可在这份问卷上，给我们一些见解
Perhaps you'd care to lend us your view on this questionnaire, sir.
不...你做得很好
No, no, no. You were doing fine.
你很有礼，而且能容纳礼貌
You had been courteous and receptive to courtesy.
你对迈克斯的尴尬说话，也表现得很信任
You had established trust with the embarrassing truth about Miggs.
至于你这份拙劣的问卷
And now this ham-handed segue into your questionnaire.
就不行了
It won't do.
我只是要求你看看它，你做不做随便你
I'm only asking you to look at this. Either you will or you won't.
对，若克劳福要从学校找人帮忙
Yeah. Jack Crawford must be very busy indeed...
他一定很忙了
if he's recruiting help from the student body.
忙于追捕那个新手水牛比尔吧
Busy hunting that new one, Buffalo Bill.
他真是个坏孩子
What a naughty boy he is.
你可知道为何他，被称为水牛比尔？
Do you know why he's called "Buffalo Bill"?
请告诉我，报纸上没有说
Please tell me. The newspapers won't say.
是来自堪萨斯城，凶案组的一个笑话
It started as a joke in Kansas City Homicide.
他们说“这个人喜欢剥他猎物的皮”
They said, "This one likes to skin his humps."
史达琳探员，你认为为什么...
Why do you think...
他要剥她们的皮？
he removes their skins, Agent Starling?
用你的敏锐来振奋我一下吧
Thrill me with your acumen.
这样做令他兴奋
It excites him.
大部分的连环杀手都会保存受害人身上的东西作为纪念品
Most serial killers keep trophies from their victims.
-我可没有　-对
- I didn't. - No.
你吃了他们
No, you ate yours.
把那个传过来吧
You send that through now.
你以为凭这份拙劣的东西，便可以分析我？
You think you can dissect me with this blunt little tool?
不是！我相信你的学识...
No! I thought that your knowledge...
你很有野心，是不是？
You're so ambitious, aren't you?
可知道你拿着那个高级皮包，穿着廉价鞋子像个什么？
You know what you look like, with your good bag and your cheap shoes?
像个土包子
You look like a rube.
一个干净，忙碌，带点品味的土包子
A well-scrubbed, hustling rube with a little taste.
虽然你衣食无忧地成长...
Nutrition has given you some length of bone...
你不外乎是个白种低下层的人
but you're not more than one generation from white trash...
是不是，史达琳探员？
are you, Agent Starling?
你极力想摆脱口音...
The accent you've tried so desperately to shed...
地道的西维吉尼亚州腔调
pure West Virginia.
你父亲是个矿工吗？
Is your father a coal miner?
那盏灯可有令他满身臭气？
Does he stink of the lamp?
我知道那些男孩怎样迅速搭上你，在汽车后座里乱摸
I know how quickly the boys found you, all those tedious, sticky fumblings...
你却想着走出去
in the back seats of cars, while you dreamed of getting out.
走去天涯海角
Getting anywhere.
直走到联邦调查局
Getting all the way to the FBI.
你很有观察力
You see a lot, doctor.
但你能否用你敏锐的观察力...
But are you strong enough to point that...
来分析自己？
high-powered perception at yourself?
怎么样？
What about it?
不如你探究一下自己，把观察所得写下来
Why don't you look at yourself and write down what you see?
或者你害怕这样做吧
Or maybe you're afraid to.
曾经有一个人口调查员想测试我
A census taker once tried to test me.
我把他的肝配蚕豆吃了
I ate his liver with some fava beans...
还有美味的红酒呢
and a nice Chianti.
小史达琳，你飞回学校去吧
You fly back to school now, little Starling.
飞吧...
Fly, fly, fly.
我咬我的手腕...
I bit my wrist...
这样才能死掉
so I could die.
看这些血
Look at the blood!
吓到你了
Gotcha.
迈克斯！你这个混蛋！
Miggs! You stupid fuck!
史达琳探员！回来！史达琳探员
Agent Starling! Come back! Agent Starling! Agent Starling!
我不会让那种事情再发生，我讨厌不礼貌的
I would not have had that happen. Discourtesy is ugly to me.
-那么做这个测验吧　-不做，但我会令你开心的
- Then do this test! - No, but I will make you happy.
-我会给你一个大好机会　-什么？
- I'll give you a chance at your love. - What?
升职，听着，你自我反省一下，克丽丝・史达琳
Advancement. Listen. Look deep within yourself, Clarice Starling.
找出我从前的病人莫菲小姐
Go seek out Miss Mofet, an old patient of mine. M-O-F-E-T.
我相信迈克斯不会这么快发作的...
I don't think Miggs could manage again so soon...
虽然他是疯的，快去
even though he is crazy. Go now!
你好，比尔
Hi, Bill.
-爸爸　-克丽丝
- Daddy! - Hey, Clarice.
-爸爸，你有没有抓到坏人？　-没有，他们跑掉了
- Did you get any bad guys, Daddy? - No, angel. They all got away.
该死
Ah, shoot.
联邦调查局，举手，别动！
FBI! Hands up! Don't move!
转过身来，把双手放在后面，好的
Turn around. Hands behind your back. Thumbs up.
史达琳，你已经死了
You're dead, Starling.
强生，进入和指挥都做得很好，史达琳，你哪里有危险？
Johnson, good entry, good command. Starling, where's your danger area?
-在角落　-你有没有检查过它？
- In the corner. - Did you check it?
-没有，长官　-所以你已经死了
- No, sir. - That's why you're dead.
3109？
3-1-0-9?
打破门或窗闯入或者撤退
Breaking doors or windows to enter or exit.
404号规条呢？
Rule 404?
（巴尔的摩心理医生，获得最高荣誉）
（著名心理医生被控谋杀）
（食人狂魔审讯带来新的恐怖）
克丽丝，你的电话，是教官
Clarice, phone. It's the guru.
克劳福？谢谢，雅戴
Crawford? Thanks, Ardelia.
-史达琳？　-长官
- Starling? - Sir.
迈克斯死了
Miggs is dead.
死了？
Dead?
怎会的？
How?
守卫听到汉尼拔・莱达下午时对他低声说话
The orderly heard Lecter whispering to him all afternoon.
他们在夜间巡查时，发现他吞掉自己的舌头
They found him at bed check. He'd swallowed his tongue.
史达琳？
Starling?
我还在听，我只是...
Yeah. I'm still here, sir. I just...
我不知道对这件事该有何感想
I don't know how to feel about this.
你不用感想什么，莱达这样做只是为了自娱
You don't have to feel any way. Lecter did it to amuse himself.
我明白今天很难受
Look, I know it got ugly today...
但你提到莫菲，有后续行动吗？
but you mentioned a name, "Mofet." Any follow-up on her?
他在被捕前，把大部分病人的病历销毁了
He destroyed most of his patients' histories prior to capture...
所以没有莫菲的记录
so there's no record of anyone named Mofet.
我觉得“你自己”这个参考资料，对莱达来说太造作了
But I thought the "yourself' reference was too hokey for Lecter...
我想起他是来自巴尔的摩，便翻查电话簿
so I figured he's from Baltimore, and I looked in the phone book.
那里有一间叫“你自己”的自助式仓库
And there's a "Your Self' storage facility...
在巴尔的摩市外围
right outside of downtown Baltimore, sir.
31号仓已经租了十年...
Unit 31 was leased...
租金是全数预缴的
for 10 years, prepaid in full.
合约是以一个...
The contract was in the name...
是赫斯达・莫菲小姐的人定的
of a Miss Hester Mofet.
自从1980年就没有人来过了？
So nobody's been in here since 1980?
以我所知是没有
Not to my knowledge.
我的顾客都很重视私隐权的
Privacy is a great concern to my customers.
对，我答应不会扰乱任何东西
Yes, I won't disturb anything, I promise.
我很快便会离开
I'll be out of here before you know it.
-要帮忙吗？　-好的
- May I help you? - Yes, actually.
这里
Here.
-它被卡着　-明天可以叫我的儿子来
- It's stuck. - We could return tomorrow with my son.
他怎么样？
What about him?
我本可叫我的司机帮你，但他讨厌体力劳动
I would ask my driver to help you, but he detests physical labor.
是吧
Right.
你别走开，我很快回来
You stay here. I'll be back in one minute.
它被卡着，请你把那支电筒给我
It's stuck. Will you hand me that flashlight?
如果这道门跌下来...
If this door should fall down...
或者有什么意外...
or anything else...
这是我们巴尔的摩办公室的电话号码
this is the number for our Baltimore office.
他们知道你跟我在一起的
They know that you're with me.
-如果有意外就找他们吧　-好的，史达琳小姐
- Call them if anything should happen. - Yes, Miss Starling.
克丽丝，他们在等你
Clarice. Here, they're waiting for you.
小心
Watch your step.
“赫斯达・莫菲”是拼字猜谜吧？
Hester Mofet. It's an anagram, isn't it, doctor?
意思是“我其余的东西”
Hester Mofet: "The rest of me"?
那表示车库是你租的？
"Miss The Rest Of Me," meaning that you rented that garage?
谢谢
Thank you.
你止血了
Your bleeding has stopped.
怎么...？
How did...?
没有大碍的
It's nothing.
只是皮外伤
It's just a scratch.
莱达医生，那瓶里的头颅是谁的？
Dr. Lecter, whose head is in that bottle?
为什么你不问我，关于水牛比尔的事？
Why don't you ask me about Buffalo Bill?
你知道他的事？
Do you know something about him?
如果我看过档案可能知道的，你可以替我拿
I might if I saw the case file. You could get that for me.
谈谈莫菲小姐吧，你要我去找他
Let's talk about Miss Mofet. You wanted me to find him.
他的真名是班哲文・赖普，是我的前病患
His real name is Benjamin Raspail. A former patient of mine...
他的恋爱对象，有点怪异
whose romantic attachments ran to, shall we say, the exotic.
我没有杀他，只是把他藏起来，就像我发现他时的样子
I did not kill him, merely tucked him away, very much as I found him...
在他错过了三次约会之后
after he'd missed three appointments.
若你没有杀他，那么是谁杀？
If you didn't kill him, who did?
谁知道？对他来说是件好事
Who can say? Best thing for him, really.
他的治疗没有功效
His therapy was going nowhere.
他的裙子，化妆...
His dress, makeup...
赖普是个异性装扮癖好者？
Raspail was a transvestite?
生活上？不是，只是普通的躁狂抑郁
In life? Oh, no. Garden variety manic-depressive.
乏味，非常乏味
Tedious, very tedious.
现在我把他看成是一个实验
I now think of him as an experiment.
一个没经验的杀手尝试转变
A fledgling killer's first effort at transformation.
你看到他时有何感觉？
How did you feel when you saw him, Clarice?
初时很害怕，后来...
Scared at first, then...
便很振奋
exhilarated.
克劳福在提拔你，是吗？
Jack Crawford is helping your career, isn't he?
看来你们互相倾慕呢
Apparently, he likes you and you like him too.
我从没有想过
I never thought about it.
你认为克劳福对你有遐想吗？
Do you think Jack Crawford wants you, sexually?
他年纪大很多，你对他可有想入非非？
He is much older, but do you think he visualizes scenarios, exchanges?
跟你做爱？
Fucking you?
我没有兴趣，这是迈克斯会说的那种话
That doesn't interest me. It's the sort of thing that Miggs would say.
不再是了
Not anymore.
谢谢你，巴尼
Thank you, Barney.
你的画呢？
What happened to your drawings?
惩罚，为了迈克斯那件事，像那个传道节目...
Punishment, you see, for Miggs. Just like that gospel program.
你离开后他们就会调高声音
When you leave, they'll turn the volume way up.
奇顿医生喜欢这些折磨伎俩
Dr. Chilton does enjoy his petty torments.
你说转变是什么意思？
What did you mean by "transformation," doctor?
克丽丝，我在这里八年了
I've been in this room for eight years now, Clarice.
我知道在我有生之年，他们都不会释放我
I know they will never ever let me out while I'm alive.
我想要的是一个景观
What I want is a view.
我想要一个看到树和水的窗户
I want a window where I can see a tree or even water.
我想去一间远离奇顿医生的联邦监狱
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton.
你说“没经验的杀手”，是什么意思？
What did you mean by "fledgling killer"?
你是否说他已经再次杀人？
Are you saying he's killed again?
我根据案件的证据，给你对水牛比尔...
I'm offering you a psychological profile on Buffalo Bill...
作心理分析
based on the case evidence.
我会帮你抓到他
I'll help you catch him, Clarice.
你知道他是谁，是不是？
You know who he is, don't you?
告诉我谁把你的病人斩首了
Tell me who decapitated your patient, doctor.
愿意等待的人都有好报的
All good things to those who wait.
我已经等了，但杰克能等多久？
I've waited, Clarice. But how long can you and old Jackie-boy wait?
我们的小比尔一定正在找寻着，下一位特别的女士了
Our little Billy must already be searching for that next special lady.
（田纳西州孟斐斯市）
小猫咪
Hey, little cheeper.
我快来了
I'll be right there.
天啊！
Jeez!
要我帮忙吗？
Can I help you with that?
可以吗？
Would you?
当然可以
Sure.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不用客气，你好像是伤残人士
That's all right. You look kind of handicapped.
是的，我搬到这里但搬不上货车
Yeah. I got it this far, I just can't get it up in the truck by myself.
来吧，抓着，上！
Here, grab this. Up!
好的
Okay.
把它放下吧，很好
Just set it down. That's good.
你上车，我想把它推进去
Get in the truck. I want to push it all the way up.
真的很谢谢你
I really appreciate this. Thank you.
放到后面去
Just go all the way back.
行了吗？
Okay. Is this good?
行了，很好
Yeah, that's good.
-真好　-好的
- That's great. - Okay.
你大概穿十四号吧？
Say, are you about a size 14?
什么？
Sorry?
（十四号）
好
Good.
好极了...
Oh, good. Good.
抓着
Holds!
一！
Ones!
史达琳！
Starling!
出去，我们走吧
Outside. Let's go.
仙蒂，进场代替史达琳，来吧
Cindy, in the ring for Starling. Let's go!
收拾你的装备
Pack your field gear.
-我们会跟克劳福一起去　-去哪里？
- You're going with Crawford. - Where?
在西维吉尼亚，发现了一名女子尸体
Found a girl's body in West Virginia.
她在水里一周了，看来是水牛比尔做的
Been in the water a week. Looks like Buffalo Bill.
（西维吉尼亚州克莱县）
（联邦调查局）
让她们活上三天，我们不明白原因
Keeps them alive for three days. We don't know why.
死前没有强奸或虐待的迹象
No evidence of rape or physical abuse prior to death.
这些伤口都是死后造成的
All the mutilation you see there is postmortem.
三天...
Okay, three days...
然后他开枪射死她们，剥皮和弃尸
then he shoots them, skins them and dumps them
每个尸体弃置在不同的河上
Each body in a different river.
河水冲走了证据
The water leaves us no trace evidence of any kind.
那是第一个，费迪嘉・拜姆
That's Fredrica Bimmel, the first one.
她的尸体是唯一被他沈下去的
Her body was the only one he weighted down.
实际上，她是第三个被发现的
So actually, she was the third girl found.
继她之后，他变得懒惰了
After her, he got lazy.
好的，我们看看
Okay, let's see.
圆圈是那些女子被掳走的位置，箭嘴是尸体被发现的地点
Circles where the girls were abducted. Arrows where their bodies were found.
今天这个被冲到这里来，在西维吉尼亚州埃尔克河被发现
This new one today washed up here. Elk River, West Virginia.
史达琳，仔细看看，告诉我你有什么发现
Look at him, Starling. Tell me what you see.
他是个白种男人
Well, he's a white male.
连环杀手倾向于在自己的族群中猎杀
Serial killers tend to hunt within their own ethnic groups.
他不是个流浪者，他有自己的独立房子
He's not a drifter. He's got his own house, not an apartment.
-为什么？　-他下毒手时，需要私人地方
- Why? - What he does with them takes privacy.
他年约三四十岁，孔武有力
He's in his 30s or 40s. He's got real physical strength.
还有中年人的自制能力，谨慎而准绳
Combined with an older man's self-control. He's cautious, precise.
他从来不冲动，也不会罢休
And he's never impulsive. He'll never stop.
为什么
Why not?
他已经迷上了这回事，而且越来越熟练
He's got a real taste for it now, and he's getting better at his work.
不错呢，有问题吗？
Not bad, Starling. Questions?
有的
Yes, sir.
你没有提及我报告里的任何资料
You haven't mentioned anything about the information in my report...
或者莱达医生的提议
or Dr. Lecter's offer, sir.
我正在考虑中
I'm considering it.
所以你派我去病院
That's why you sent me in there, isn't it?
找他协助缉捕水牛比尔？
To get his help on Buffalo Bill, sir?
如果那是事实...
Well, if that was the case, then I just...
我希望可以早点知道罢了
I just wish I was in on it, that's all.
若以真正目的派你去，莱达会识破的
If I'd sent you in there with a real agenda, Lecter would have known it.
他会把你玩弄，什么也不会说
He would have toyed with you, then turned to stone.
（格里殡仪馆）
打扰了，柏金斯警长？
Excuse me, Sheriff Perkins?
这些是联邦调查局人员
These are the FBI people.
柏金斯警长，我是杰克・克劳福，这是泰瑞和史达琳
Sheriff Perkins, Jack Crawford, FBI. Special Agent Terry, Agent Starling.
感谢邀请我们来到你们的管辖区
We appreciate being invited to your jurisdiction.
是州政府检察部找你们的
Somebody from the state attorney's office called you.
我们会通力合作，但现在...
We'll extend you every courtesy, but right now...
警长
Sheriff...
我认为该在私底下谈论这类性罪行的细节
this type of sex crime has aspects I'd just as soon discuss in private.
你明白吧？
Know what I mean?
奥加，去教堂叫区医生来
Oscar, fetch Dr. Akin from the chapel.
我们在后面这里
We're back here.
叫拉玛弹奏完毕后过来
Tell Lamar to come on when he's finished playing his music.
是的，我们稍后会传过来
Yeah, we'll be sending in a minute.
行了
It's working.
我要组成六线联系，芝加哥，底特律...
I need a six-way link up. Chicago, Detroit...
什么？
What? What?
对不起
Excuse me.
对不起，各位警官先生，听着
Excuse me, officers and gentlemen. Listen here, now.
我们要替她做一些事情
There's things we need to do for her.
你们把她带来了这里，她的家人会感谢...
Y'all brought her this far, and her folks would thank you if they could...
你们的善意和体谅
for your kindness and your sensitivity.
请离开吧，让我们照顾她好了
Please, go on now, and let us take care of her.
走吧
Go on, now.
谢谢
Thank you.
很好
Okay, good.
是的，埃尔克河，准备传送
Yeah, that's right. Elk River. Stand by for transmission.
瑞
Ray.
大家来看看她吧
Doctor, Lamar. Let's take a look at her.
天啊
Jesus...
史达琳，行了
Okay, Starling.
胸骨上有星形的伤口
Star-shaped contact entrance wound over the sternum.
上面有个枪口印记
A muzzle stamp at the top.
-死于非命　-死于非命
- Wrongful death. - Wrongful death.
她要被送去克拉斯顿的病理学家那里
She'll have to go to the state pathologist's at Claxton.
我还是回去那个丧礼了
Well, I better get back to that service.
利玛会帮你们的
Lamar will help you.
老天爷
Lord Almighty.
你还观察到什么？
What else do you see, Starling?
她不是当地人
Well, she's not local.
她穿了三个耳洞，还有...
Her ears are pierced three times and there's...
闪亮的指甲油，看来是城市人
glitter nail polish. It looks like town to me.
她有两只指甲断了
Two of her fingernails are broken off...
指甲下有泥土和沙粒
and there's dirt or grit under them.
她好像想爬过一些什么似的
It looks like she's tried to claw her way through something.
瑞，替她的牙齿拍照，稍后传真到失踪人口组
Ray, get pictures of her teeth. We'll fax them to Missing Persons.
好的
Right.
再拍一张
Let's do another.
她喉咙里有东西
She's got something in her throat.
当尸体被捞出水面时
When a body comes out of the water...
口里总会有些树叶之类的东西
lots of times there's leaves and things in the mouth.
那是什么？
What is that?
豆荚吗？
Some kind of seedpod?
不，是一只虫茧
No, sir. That's a bug cocoon.
没可能自己走进去的
There's no way that could get way down in there.
除非有人把它塞进去
Not unless somebody shoved it in there.
我们把她翻过来会较易采指纹
She'll be easier to print when we turn her.
帮帮我
Lamar, give me a hand?
好的
Yes, sir, I will.
你看这些是什么？
Oh, Jack. What do you make of these?
跟其他死者的形状不同，拍几张大特写
Different configuration than the other victims. Get close-ups.
死者的皮肤...
Victim's skin removed...
在臀部以上，有两块菱形的皮肤被剥去
in two diamond-shaped sections above the buttocks.
伤口跟第二或第三节脊骨平衡
Exit wound level with the second or third thoracic vertebrae...
距离右肩胛骨大约六英寸
approximately six inches from the right shoulder blade.
史达琳
Starling...
我对那个警长说，我们不该在女人面前谈
when I told that sheriff we shouldn't talk in front of a woman...
那令你很气恼吧？
that burned you, didn't it?
那只是个烟幕，我要打发他走
It was just smoke, Starling. I had to get rid of him
是很要紧
It matters, Mr. Crawford.
探员们想看你怎样应付
Cops look at you to see how to act.
很要紧的
It matters.
我明白了
Point taken.
手腕周围有被捆绑的痕迹
Ligature marks found around wrists...
足踝就没有
not around the ankles.
显示死后才剥皮的
This would indicate that the skinning was postmortem.
时间到了，轮到我
Time, Pilch. My move.
-不公平，你用食物引诱它　-真无赖，仍然是轮到我
- No fair! You lured him with produce. - Tough noogies. It's still my turn.
宝贝，慢慢来
Nice and slow, baby.
若那只甲虫推动你的棋子，也算数吗？
If the beetle moves one of your men, does that still count?
当然算数，你怎么玩的？
Of course it counts. How do you play?
史达琳探员？
Agent Starling?
这东西从哪里来的？
Where the heck did this come from?
它粘糊糊的
It's practically mush.
在一个被杀死者身上找到的，尸体在埃尔克河里
It was found in a murder victim. The body was in the Elk River.
是水牛比尔干的吗？
It's Buffalo Bill, isn't it?
我不能透露
I can't tell you any more.
我们在电台听到
We heard it on the radio.
这是一宗真实谋杀案的线索？酷
You mean this is a clue from a real murder case? Cool!
别管他，他是无名小卒
Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.
小角天蛾，可能是...
Sphingid Ceratomia, maybe...
它是只大吸血鬼
Boy, he's a big sucker.
好吧
Okay...
查看一下形态学
let's check morphology.
史达琳探员，你不查案时会做什么？
What do you do when you're not detecting, Agent Starling?
做个学生
Try to be a student, Dr. Pilcher.
你去过吃起司汉堡和喝啤酒吗？
You ever go out for cheeseburgers and beer?
那有趣的招牌酒？
The amusing house wine?
博士，你是否对我有意？
Are you hitting on me, doctor?
-是的　-找到了！
- Yes. - Gotcha!
你找到什么？
What do you got?
史达琳探员，这个是阴间冥河
Agent Starling, meet Mr. Acherontia Styx.
真奇怪
Weird.
认识它的人多叫它做骷髅飞蛾
Better known to his friends as the Death's-head moth.
它从哪里来的？
Where does it come from?
这正是古怪之处，它们只活在亚洲
That's what's strange. They only live in Asia.
它们是从进口的卵子繁殖的
They're specially raised from imported eggs.
有人饲养这只东西，喂它吃蜜糖和茄类植物
Somebody grew this guy. Fed him honey and nightshade.
给它保暖
Kept him warm.
有人很爱护它
Somebody loved him.
你在哪里？
Where are you?!
放我出去！
Let me out of here!
喂！
Hey!
救我！
Please help me!
求你救我
Help me, please!
干嘛你不答我？求求你！
Why won't you answer me?! Please!
-各位早，我是唐娜・佛鲁兹　-我是报导体育的金・凯素
- Good morning. I'm Donna Ferucchi. - I'm Gene Cassel with sports.
我是提姆・兰汉，今早的头条新闻如下
And I'm Tim Langhorn. Our top story this morning:
马丁参议员的25岁女儿凯瑟琳・马丁...
Catherine Martin, the 25-year-old daughter of Senator Ruth Martin...
一度被列为失踪人士
listed as a missing person...
相信她已经被称为“水牛比尔”的杀手绑架
is believed to have been kidnapped by the killer known as "Buffalo Bill."
孟斐斯市警方说，已确认出该名失踪女孩的衬衫
Memphis police say the missing girl's blouse has been identified...
它后面被割破，案情耐人寻味
sliced up the back, in what has become a kind of grim calling card.
凯瑟琳是田纳西州的共和党...
Young Catherine is the only daughter of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin...
马丁参议员的独生女
the Republican senator from Tennessee.
虽然这宗绑架案没有政治动机
And while her kidnapping is not considered politically motivated...
但政府高层仍然相当重视
it has stirred the government to its highest levels.
正在佛蒙特州滑雪的总统
Reached for comment on the ski slopes of Vermont...
接受访问时表示，“极度关注”事件
the president himself said to be, and I quote, "intensely concerned."
马丁参议员于较早前，录影了以下的呼吁
Just moments ago, Senator Martin taped this dramatic personal plea:
我向挟持小女的人说话
I'm speaking, now, to the person holding my daughter.
凯瑟琳是非常温文和善良的
Catherine is very gentle and kind.
你跟她谈谈就知道
Talk to her and you'll see.
你有力量，你有控制权
You have the power. You are in charge.
我知道你感受到爱和善心的
I know you can feel love and compassion.
你有一个向全世界展示的大好机会...
You have a wonderful chance to show the whole world...
就是你是善良而坚强的
that you can be merciful, as well as strong.
你有能力善待凯瑟琳...
That you're big enough to treat Catherine better...
比这个世界待你更好
than the world has treated you.
你有此能力
You have that power.
求你，我的女儿是凯瑟琳
Please. My daughter is Catherine.
真是聪明
Boy, that's smart.
真的很聪明
Jesus, that's really smart.
她不断重复那个名字
She keeps repeating the name.
若他视凯瑟琳为一个人而非物件，就难以下毒手
If he sees Catherine as a person, not an object, it's harder to tear her up.
求你放了我的女儿
Please, release my little girl.
史达琳小姐，你来我的医院干什么？
What you're doing, Ms. Starling, is coming into my hospital...
并第三次拒绝跟我分享资料
and refusing to share information with me for the third time.
这不过是赖普案的例行后续
Sir, I told you this is just a routine follow-up on the Raspail...
他是我的病人，我有知情权
He is my patient. I have rights.
我明白
I understand that.
史达琳小姐，我不是个笨蛋
Look, I am not just some turnkey, Miss Starling.
这是检察官的电话号码
This is the number for the U.S. Attorney.
请你跟他谈，或者让我执行任务，明白吗？
Please, either discuss it with him or let me do my job, you understand?
如果你的分析能帮助我们抓到水牛比尔...
If your profile helps us catch Buffalo Bill...
及时救出凯瑟琳・马丁...
in time to save Catherine Martin...
参议员答应把你转送到...
the senator promises you a transfer to the VA Hospital...
它位于纽约奥尼达公园，可看到附近的园林景色的医院
at Oneida Park, New York, with a view of the woods nearby.
当然仍是高度设防的
Maximum security still applies, of course.
你可以阅读书籍
You'd have reasonable access to books.
最好的是...
Best of all, though...
你每年可以离开医院一周
one week of the year, you get to leave the hospital...
去这里
and go here:
普拉姆岛
Plum Island.
在那一星期里，你都可以在沙滩漫步
Every day of that week, you may walk on the beach
也可以在海中畅泳一小时
You may swim in the ocean for up to one hour...
当然是受特种部队的监视
under SWAT team surveillance, of course.
给你的
And there you have it.
水牛比尔的档案副本
A copy of the Buffalo Bill case file.
参议员的建议书副本
A copy of the senator's offer.
这个建议是无商讨余地的
This offer is non-negotiable and final.
凯瑟琳・马丁死了你就一无所得
Catherine Martin dies, you get nothing.
普拉姆岛动物病症研究中心
Plum Island Animal Disease Research Center.
听来很吸引
Sounds charming.
那个岛有一流的海滩
That's only part of the island. There's a very nice beach.
岛上有燕鸥巢，有漂亮的...
Terns nest there. There's beautiful...
燕鸥？
Terns?
如果我帮你，也会是我们的转机
If I help you, Clarice, it will be "turns" with us too.
我们互相交换资料吧
Quid pro quo. I tell you things, you tell me things.
但不是关于这宗案件，是关于你自己
Not about this case, though. About yourself.
交换，好不好？
Quid pro quo. Yes or no?
好吗？克丽丝，可怜的凯瑟琳在等着
Yes or no, Clarice? Poor little Catherine is waiting.
好吧
Go, doctor.
你最糟的童年记忆是什么？
What is your worst memory of childhood?
家父去世
The death of my father.
告诉我，别说谎，我会知道的
Tell me about it. And don't lie, or I'll know.
他是镇上的警长
He was a town marshal...
有一晚他遇上两个，从药房走出来的窃匪
and one night he surprised two burglars coming out of a drugstore.
他们向他开枪
They shot him.
他当场死亡？
Was he killed outright?
不是，他很坚强，熬了个几个月
No, he was very strong. He lasted more than a month.
我母亲在我年幼时去世
My mother died when I was very young, so...
自始父亲就成为我的一切
my father had become the whole world to me...
他离开后，我一无所有，我那时十岁
and when he left me, I had nothing. I was 10 years old.
你很坦白
You're very frank, Clarice.
我相信私底下结识你，会很有意思的
I think it would be quite something to know you in private life.
交换资料
Quid pro quo, doctor.
谈谈西维州小姐吧，她是否身材肥大？
So tell me about Miss West Virginia. Was she a large girl?
是的
Yes.
大屁股，肉团团？
Big through the hips, roomy?
死者们全都是
They all were.
还有什么线索？
What else?
她的喉咙被异物塞住
She had an object deliberately inserted into her throat.
还没有正式公布的，我们不知道它有何意思
Now, that hasn't been made public yet. We don't know what it means.
一只蝴蝶？
Was it a butterfly?
是的，一只飞蛾
Yes. A moth.
一小时前，我们在班哲文・赖普的头颅内也找到
Just like the one we found in Benjamin Raspail's head an hour ago.
为何他把它们放进去？
Why does he place them there, doctor?
飞蛾的特点是转变
The significance of the moth is change.
幼虫变成蝶蛹或者蛹
Caterpillar into chrysalis, or pupa...
再变成美丽的蝴蝶
and from thence into beauty.
比尔也想转变
Our Billy wants to change too.
变性癖和暴力之间是没有关连的
There's no correlation between transsexualism and violence.
-变性癖者是很被动的　-很聪明
- Transsexuals are very passive. - Clever girl.
你有捉拿到他的本领，知道吗？
You're so close to the way you're gonna catch him. Do you realize that?
不知道，为什么？
No. Tell me why.
你父亲被杀后你成了孤儿，后来怎么样？
After your father's murder you were orphaned. What happened next?
答案并非在那双廉价鞋子上
I don't imagine the answer is on those second-rate shoes, Clarice.
我去了蒙大拿州，跟我母亲的表妹夫妇同住
I went to live with my mother's cousin and her husband in Montana.
他们有一个牧场
They had a ranch.
牧牛场？
Was it a cattle ranch?
牧羊和马
Sheep and horses.
你在那里住了多久？
How long did you live there?
两个月
Two months.
为何时间这么短？
Why so briefly?
我跑掉了
I ran away.
为什么？牧场主人逼你口交？
Why, Clarice? Did the rancher make you perform fellatio?
他有没有鸡奸你？
Did he sodomize you?
没有，他是个很正派的人
No. He was a very decent man.
交换资料
Quid pro quo, doctor.
比尔不是个真正的变性癖者
Billy is not a real transsexual.
但他以为自己是，他想那样
But he thinks he is. He tries to be.
我相信他想做很多东西
He's tried to be a lot of things, I expect.
你说我有捉拿他的本领，是何意思？
You said I was very close to the way we'd catch him. What did you mean?
有三间主要做变性手术的中心
There are three major centers for transsexual surgery:
约翰・霍金斯，明尼苏达州大学，和哥伦布医疗中心
Johns Hopkins, the University of Minnesota, and Columbus Medical Center.
若比尔向它们申请做变性手术，而又被拒绝...
I wouldn't be surprised if Billy applied for sex reassignment...
我也不会感到惊讶
at one or all of them, and been rejected.
他们根据什么来拒绝他？
On what basis would they reject him?
试找寻跟暴力有关的童年创伤吧
Look for severe childhood disturbances associated with violence.
比尔并非天生是个罪犯
Our Billy wasn't born a criminal, Clarice...
是经过多年来惯常的，虐待所导致的
he was made one through years of systematic abuse.
他讨厌自己的身份
Billy hates his own identity, you see...
他以为那是令他成为变性癖者的原因
and he thinks that makes him a transsexual...
但他的病征要更凶残...
but his pathology is a thousand times more savage...
和可怕千倍
and more terrifying.
它涂润肤液在身上，它听到指示总会依着做
It rubs the lotion on its skin. It does this whenever it's told.
先生，我的家人会付钱的
Mister, my family will pay cash.
无论你要多少赎金，他们都会付
Whatever ransom you're asking for, they'll pay it.
它涂润肤液在身上，否则又要挨打了
It rubs the lotion on its skin or else it gets the hose again.
是的，珍宝，她会挨打的
Yes, she will, Precious. She'll get the hose.
好吧...
Okay, okay, okay.
我做吧
Okay, I'll do it.
好的
Okay.
先生，如果你放我走，我答应不会起诉你
Mister, if you let me go, I won't press charges. I promise.
我妈是个重要人物
See, my mom is a real important woman.
相信你也知道吧
I guess you already know that.
它把润肤液放在篮里
Now it places the lotion in the basket.
求求你！
Please!
求求你，我想回家
Please, I want to go home.
我想回家！求求你！放我吧
I want to go home! Please! Please let me.
把润肤液放在篮里
It places the lotion in the basket.
我想见我妈妈，求你放我吧
I want to see my mommy. Please let me.
我想再见到我妈妈，我想...
I want to see my mom again. I want...
我想见我妈妈
I want to see my mom.
把那他妈的润肤液放在篮里！
Put the fucking lotion in the basket!
你仍然以为可在沙滩漫步，和看鸟儿吗？
You still think you're gonna walk on some beach and see the birdies?
不会了
I don't think so.
我找过凯瑟琳・马丁参议员
I called Senator Ruth Martin.
她没听过跟你有任何协议
She never heard of any deal with you.
他们骗你
They scammed you, Hannibal.
出去
Stand outside.
把门关上
And shut the door.
巴尼
Barney.
从没有跟马丁参议员作过协议，但现在有了
There never was a deal with Senator Martin, but there is now.
是我议定的
I designed it.
当然，我也为自己的利益，定下了一些条件
Of course, I worked in a few conditions for my own benefit as well.
说出水牛比尔的名字
Identify Buffalo Bill by name...
如果那个女孩及时被发现
and if the girl is found in time...
你就会被转送到田纳西州的丛树山州立监狱
you'll be transferred to Brushy Mountain State Prison in Tennessee.
回答我
Answer me, Hannibal.
你现在回答我
You answer me now...
否则，天啊，你休想离开这个牢房
or, by God, you'll never leave this cell.
水牛比尔是谁？
Who is Buffalo Bill?
他的名字是路易斯
His first name is Louis.
其余的我只会在田纳西州，亲自对参议员说
I'll tell the rest to the Senator herself, but only in Tennessee.
我也有几个条件
And I have a few conditions of my own.
替他梳洗一下，准备出发
Clean him up and get him ready to go.
杰克，汉尼拔・莱达正被转送往孟斐斯途中
Jack, Hannibal Lecter is being transferred to Memphis.
转送？
Transferred?
你可有个见习生，冒参议员之名，向莱达提出一个虚假的建议？
Did you have a trainee make a phony offer to Lecter in the senator's name?
是我的主意，我逼不得已
I rolled the dice. I had to.
她气疯了
Well, she's mad as hell, Jack.
司法部的保罗・肯度拿来了
Paul Krendler's here from Justice.
她要求他在孟斐斯接手
She's asking him to take over in Memphis.
（孟斐斯市国际机场）
莱达医生，欢迎到孟斐斯
Welcome to Memphis, Dr. Lecter.
我是鲍尔探员，这位是派屈克警长
I'm Lieutenant Boyle. This is Sergeant Patrick.
我们会像你待我们那么好的
We'll treat you as good as you treat us.
你乖乖的，就会得到舒服的待遇
You be a gentleman, you'll get three hots and a cot.
长官，请在这里签名，我们作合法的移交
Sir, if you sign right here, we'll have us a legal transfer.
用我的吧
Here, sir, use mine.
马丁参议员
Senator Martin...
汉尼拔・莱达医生
Dr. Hannibal Lecter.
莱达医生
Dr. Lecter...
我带了一份宣誓书，保证你新的权利
l've brought an affidavit guaranteeing your new rights.
在我签署前你要看看的
You'll want to read it before I sign.
我不会为了小利益，而耽误你或凯瑟琳的时间
I won't waste your time or Catherine's time bargaining for petty privileges.
克丽丝・史达琳和克劳福，已经浪费了太多时间
Clarice Starling and Jack Crawford have wasted too much time already.
但愿他们没有害死，那个可怜的女孩
I only pray they haven't doomed the poor girl.
让我帮你吧，事成后我会信任你
Let me help you now. I will trust you when it is all over.
我答应你，保罗
You have my word. Paul.
水牛比尔的真名是路易斯・法兰
Buffalo Bill's real name is Louis Friend.
我只见过他一次，1980年4 5月间由我的病人...
I met him just once. He was referred to me in April or May, 1980...
班哲文・赖普转介给我的
by my patient Benjamin Raspail.
他们是爱人
They were lovers, you see.
但赖普变得很害怕
But Raspail had become very frightened.
看来路易斯谋杀了一个流浪汉
Apparently, Louis had murdered a transient...
用他的皮肤做了一些东西
and done things with the skin.
我们要他的地址和容貌特征
We need his address and a physical description.
告诉我，参议员...
Tell me, senator.
你有没有亲自哺育凯瑟琳？
Did you nurse Catherine yourself?
-什么？　-你有没有给她喂奶？
- What? - Did you breast-feed her?
-混帐　-我有的
- Now, wait a minute! - Yes. I did.
令你的乳头变得坚挺，是吗？
Toughened your nipples, didn't it?
你这个混蛋！
You son of a bitch!
把人的腿切除，他仍感到振奋
Amputate a man's leg, and he can still feel it tickling.
告诉我，妈妈，当你的小女儿被杀时
Tell me, Mom, when your little girl is on the slab...
你哪里会感到振奋？
where will it tickle you?
把这个畜生带回巴尔的摩
Take this thing back to Baltimore.
五英尺十英寸，身材魁悟，约一百八十磅
Five-foot-ten, strongly built, about 180 pounds.
金发，浅蓝色眼睛
Hair, blond. Eyes, pale blue.
他现在大约三十五岁
He'd be about 35 now.
他声称住在费城，可能是说谎
He said he lived in Philadelphia but may have lied.
我只记得这么多了，妈
That's all I can remember, Mom.
若我再想起什么，我会通知你的
But if I think of any more, I will let you know.
参议员，还有一件事
Oh, and senator, just one more thing:
你的套装很漂亮
Love your suit.
与马丁参议员，在今天较早前的会面中
In a meeting earlier today with Senator Ruth Martin...
莱达医生同意协助追缉水牛比尔
Dr. Lecter agreed to help in the investigation to find Buffalo Bill.
（谢尔比县法院大楼）
-你扮演什么角色？　-我对莱达医生的...
- How do you fit in? - My unique insight...
独特触觉促成了这次突破
into Lecter made the breakthrough.
水牛比尔叫什么名字？
Buffalo Bill's name?
这是目前有关当局的秘密
His name is now a matter of record with the proper authorities.
-可否给我们...　-我是奇顿医生
- Can you give us...? - I'm Dr. Frederick Chilton.
-怎样写法？　-奇特的奇...
- Spell it? - That's C-H...
你是奇顿医生的组员吗？
Are you with Dr. Chilton's group?
我刚在外面见到他
Well, I just saw him outside, sir.
不能有太多人接近莱达，我们接到死亡恐吓
Access to Lecter is limited. We've received death threats.
我明白的
I understand, sir.
登记和把武器放下
Log in and check your weapon.
我不能独自邀功的
I can't take all the credit myself.
马丁参议员，司法部，联邦调查局
Senator Martin, Justice Department, FBI...
巴尔的摩州立医院的人员，最困难就是...
folks at the Baltimore State Hospital. Now for the hard part:
逮捕那个疑匪
Apprehending the suspect.
对不起，我要赶飞机了
Excuse me, I have to catch a flight.
指挥台，我是杰各警员
Command desk, Officer Jacobs.
（路易斯・法兰飞禽，猥亵）
（铁）
-他们说的是事实吗？　-什么？
- Is it true what they're saying? - Huh?
他是个吸血殭尸？
He's some kind of vampire?
他们没有替他取名
They don't have a name for what he is.
小姐，你知道规矩的吧？
You do know the rules, ma'am?
知道，我以前盘问过他
Yes, I've questioned him before.
去吧
Go ahead.
克丽丝，晚安
Good evening, Clarice.
你可能想要回你的画吧
I thought you might like your drawings back.
直到你有自己的景观
Just until you get your view.
真是周到
How very thoughtful.
还是在你们破案前，克劳福派你来...
Or did Jack Crawford send you for one last wheedle...
说最后一次的花言巧语？
before you're both booted off the case?
不，是我自己想来的
No. I came because I wanted to.
人家会说我们在恋爱呢
People will say we're in love.
安克斯岛
Anthrax Island.
真是有心思，克丽丝
That was an especially nice touch, Clarice.
你画的？
Yours?
是
Yes.
对
Yeah.
很好
That was good.
但我同情可怜的凯瑟琳
Pity about poor Catherine, though.
滴答...
Ticktock, ticktock, ticktock.
你的字谜有破绽了
Your anagrams are showing, doctor.
路易斯・法兰？
Louis Friend?
是硫化铁，也叫做黄铜铁
Iron sulfide, also known as fool's gold.
克丽丝，你的毛病是，你要活得轻松一点
Oh, Clarice, your problem is, you need to get more fun out of life.
你在巴尔的摩时说了真话
You were telling me the truth back in Baltimore, sir.
现在继续吧
Please continue now.
我看过那些档案了，你看过吗？
Well, I've read the case files. Have you?
你要缉拿他的资料都在里面
Everything you need to find him is there in those pages.
-那么教我怎样做　-首要的原则
- Then tell me how. - First principles, Clarice.
是简易，读马可・奥勒利乌斯吧
Simplicity. Read Marcus Aurelius.
凡事都问：它是什么？
Of each particular thing, ask: What is it in itself?
它有什么本质？
What is its nature?
你寻找的这个人，他做什么？
What does he do, this man you seek?
杀害女人
He kills women.
不，那是次要的
No. That is incidental.
他主要是做什么？他杀人是为了满足什么？
What is the principle thing he does? What needs does he serve by killing?
愤怒
Anger...
社会认同和性困惑
social acceptance and sexual frustration...
不是！
No!
他贪图
He covets.
那是他的本性
That is his nature.
我们怎样才会开始贪图？
And how do we begin to covet, Clarice?
我们是否去寻找贪图的东西？
Do we seek out things to covet?
尝试回答吧
Make an effort to answer now.
不是，我们只是...
No, we just...
我们看见日常的东西就开始贪图
No, we begin by coveting what we see every day.
你可有感到一些眼睛在盯着你？
Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice?
你的眼睛，又可有寻找你要的东西？
And don't your eyes seek out the things you want?
有的，请你告诉我吧
All right, yes. Now, please tell me how.
不
No.
轮到你告诉我了
It is your turn to tell me, Clarice.
你再没有假期可哄骗我了
You don't have any more vacations to sell.
为何你离开那个牧场？
Why did you leave that ranch?
我们没有时间再玩这一套了
Doctor, we don't have any more time for any of this now.
但我们的时间观念是不同的
But we don't reckon time the same way, do we?
你只有这么多的时间
This is all the time you'll have.
稍后吧，请听着，我们只有五个...
Later. Please listen. We've only got five...
不，我现在要听
No! I will listen now.
父亲被杀后，你十岁就成了孤儿
Your father's murder orphaned you when you were 10.
你去了蒙大拿，跟一些养羊马的表亲同住，之后呢？
You went to live with cousins on a sheep and horse ranch in Montana. And?
我在一个早上跑掉了
And one morning I just ran away.
不是的，什么驱使你离开？
Not "just," Clarice. What set you off?
你在什么时候出发？
You started at what time?
很早，天还没亮
Early, still dark.
有东西吵醒你，是不是一个梦？
Then something woke you. Was it a dream?
是什么？
What was it?
我听到一种奇怪的声音
I heard a strange noise.
是什么？
What was it?
是...
It was...
尖叫声
screaming.
像小孩的尖叫声
Some kind of screaming, like a child's voice.
你怎么做？
What did you do?
我下楼
I went...
走出屋外
downstairs. Outside.
我偷进了壳仓
I crept up into the barn.
我很害怕看进去，但又必须看
I was so scared to look inside, but I had to.
你看见什么？克丽丝？
And what did you see, Clarice? What did you see?
一些羔羊
Lambs.
它们在尖叫
They were screaming.
他们在宰杀那些羔羊？
They were slaughtering the spring lambs?
而它们在尖叫
And they were screaming.
那你就跑掉了？
And you ran away?
不是，最初我想释放它们
No. First I tried to free them.
我打开它们的闸门
I opened the gate to their pen.
它们只是站在那里，很困惑的，不肯走
They just stood there, confused. They wouldn't run.
但你可以走，你也走了，是不是？
But you could and you did, didn't you?
是的，我抱起一只羊就拔足逃跑
Yes. I took one lamb and I ran away as fast as I could.
你去哪里？
Where were you going, Clarice?
不知道，我没有食物和水
I don't know. I didn't have any food, any water...
而且当时很冷，非常冷
and it was very cold. It was very cold.
我以为...
I thought...
我以为，至少可救到一只羊
I thought if I could save just one...
但它很重
but he was so heavy.
真的很重
He was so heavy.
我走不了几里路，警长的车就把我截住
I didn't get more than a few miles when the sheriffs car picked me up.
牧场主人很生气，把我送到博斯曼的路德会孤儿院
The rancher was so angry he sent me to a Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman.
我再没看过那个牧场了
I never saw the ranch again.
你的羊又怎么样？
What became of your lamb, Clarice?
他们把它杀了
They killed him.
有时你仍会惊醒，是吗？
You still wake up sometimes, don't you?
在黑暗中醒来...
Wake up in the dark...
听到那些羔羊的尖叫声？
and hear the screaming of the lambs?
是的
Yes.
你相信如果把凯瑟琳救了出来
And you think if you save poor Catherine...
可以令它们停止尖叫是吗？你相信如果凯瑟琳活着...
you can make them stop, don't you? You think if Catherine lives...
你就不会在黑夜中...
you won't wake up in the dark ever again...
再被那些恐怖的羊声惊醒了
to that awful screaming of the lambs.
我不知道
I don't know.
谢谢你，克丽丝
Thank you, Clarice.
谢谢你
Thank you.
告诉我他的名字
Tell me his name, doctor.
是奇顿医生吧
Dr. Chilton, I presume.
我相信你们是认识的
I think you know each other.
好吧
Okay.
-我们找到她了　-我们走吧
- We found her. - Let's go.
医生，轮到你了
It's your turn, doctor.
-出去　-说出他的名字
- Out! - Tell me his name.
抱歉，我接到命令，要把你送上飞机
Sorry, ma'am, I've got orders to put you on a plane.
走吧
Come on, now.
勇敢的克丽丝
Brave Clarice.
那些羔羊停止尖叫时，你会告诉我的，是吗？
You will let me know when those lambs stop screaming, won't you?
说出他的名字
Tell me his name, doctor!
克丽丝
Clarice!
你的档案
Your case file.
喂！
Hey!
再见，克丽丝
Goodbye, Clarice.
医生，准备好就来吧
Ready when you are, doc.
请等一会
Just another minute, please.
那个混蛋竟然要再吃晚饭
Son of a bitch demanded a second dinner.
还要极生的羊排
Lamb chops, extra rare.
不知他早餐要吃什么？动物园里的怪物？
Wonder what he wants for breakfast? Some damn thing from the zoo?
（化学喷雾）
两位，晚安
Good evening, gentlemen.
好的，医生，蹲下吧
Okay, doc. Grab some floor.
跟以前的程序一样
Same drill as before, please.
庞毕探员，准备好了
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
行了
Okay.
递给我吧
Hand me that, would you?
谢谢
Thanks.
请小心那些画
Mind the drawings, please.
谢谢你
Thank you.
庞毕，小心，他把我扣住
Pembry, watch it, he's cuffed me!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
庞毕探员，准备好就来吧
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
究竟什么回事？
What is this shit?
有人上了五楼？
Did somebody go up on five?
-没有人上过去　-叫庞毕，叫他告诉...
- No, nobody went up. - Call Pembry. Ask him to tell...
CP，五楼有枪声，重复，五楼有枪声
CP, shots fired on five. Repeat, shots fired on five.
戴德警官
Sergeant Tate!
去，五楼有枪声
Proceed. Shots fired on five.
天啊！
Holy shit!
-怎么了？　-混蛋！
- What the hell? - Bitch!
闭嘴！
Shut up!
波比，拿避弹衣来
Bobby, get the vest.
是，警官
Right, sarge.
-布莱迪，霍华，掩护　-看！
- Brady, Howard, cover... - Look!
它停了
It stopped.
封锁方圆十幢楼的范围
Seal off a 10-block radius.
召特种部队和救护车来，快点！
Get me the SWAT team and an ambulance, double quick.
我们上楼去
We're going up.
庞毕？
Pembry?!
鲍尔？
Boyle?!
天啊！
Oh, God!
去
Go.
-没有人　-没有人
- Clear. - Clear.
指挥站
Command post.
两个警员死了
Two officers down.
-没有人　-没有人
- Clear! - Clear!
警官，莱达不见了
Lecter's gone, sarge.
囚犯失踪了
Prisoner is missing.
鲍尔的配枪不见了
Boyle's gun is gone.
重复，莱达持械失踪了
Repeat. Lecter is missing and armed.
他拿走了床铺
He stripped the bed.
可能用来做绳，搜查所有窗户
Might be making a rope. Check all the windows.
救护车在哪里？
Where the fuck is my ambulance?
他仍活着的
He's alive.
戴德警官，他仍活着！
Sergeant Tate! He's alive!
扶着他，抚摸他的手，跟他说话
Get ahold of him and feel his hands. Talk to him!
说什么？
What do I say?
他是庞德吉姆，跟他说话，该死
It's Jim Pembry. Now talk to him, damn it!
莱达持械失踪了
Lecter is missing and armed.
-庞毕...你听到我吗？　-他拿了鲍尔的配枪
- Pembry. Pembry, can you hear me? - He took Boyle's gun.
庞毕发过一枪，莱达可能中了枪的
Pembry got off one round. There's a chance Lecter's hit.
继续呼吸吧
Keep breathing in and out.
你做得很好，你没事的
You're doing a good job. You look real good there.
对，你没事的
Yeah, you look... Look real good.
-准备了吗？　-来吧
- You ready? - Let's go!
-我们来吧　-好的，走吧
- Let's do it. - Okay, let's go!
很好，你支持得住的
Looking good. You're gonna make it.
没事的
Everything's just fine.
-我要作静脉注射　-乳酸林格注射液
- I need that IV now! - Lactated Ringer's.
可否拿那条带子来？氧气在哪里？
Can we get the strap? Where's the oxygen?
老兄，情况很好，镇定一点
Doing good, buddy. That's right. Stay with me here.
他不行了，去楼下，快点
We're losing him! Downstairs, quickly!
抬起！
And up!
-电梯！　-这边
- Elevator! - This way!
-让开！　-让开！
- Out of the way! - Get out of the way!
CP叫戴德
CP to Tate.
收到，我是戴德
Roger, lieutenant. Tate here.
我现在乘电梯送庞毕下来
I'm on the elevator bringing Pembry down.
他看来支持得住
He seems to be hanging on.
最高的三层楼封锁了
Top three floors secured.
主要楼梯封锁了
Main stairwell secured.
我们相信他在二楼
We think he's on two.
戴德，你听到吗？
Tate, you still with me?
我们颇肯定他在二楼
We're pretty sure he's somewhere on two, sir.
通话暂时完毕
That's all for now. Over.
他在电梯顶
He's on the roof of the elevator.
好的，大家来
Okay, guys.
我看到他
I see him.
他的手旁边有一支枪，他没有动
There's a gun by his hand. He's not moving.
-警告，我们要生擒他　-知道
- One warning. We need him alive. - Got it.
莱达？
Lecter?
把双手放在头上
Put your hands on your head.
向腿射一枪
One in the leg.
没有动静
No movement.
约翰，不要开枪，我们要进入电梯
Johnny, hold your fire. We're coming into the car.
我们会打开盖口
We're opening the hatch.
小心他的手
Watch his hands.
如果有开火，会是我们发的，确定
If there's any fire, it'll come from us. Affirm.
明白
Got it.
孟斐斯医院，这是26号车
Memphis General, this is Unit 26.
我们会送来一名五十岁男警
We're inbound with a 50-year-old male officer...
他面部有严重割伤
with severe facial lacerations.
他全身出现抽搐，情况严重
He had grand mal seizure activity. He's postdictal now.
-收到　-重要器官情况良好
- I copy. - Vital signs are good.
-血压是130/90　-90？
- Pressure is 130l90. - Ninety?
对，是90，脉搏84
Yeah, that's right, 90. Pulse, 84.
我们给他注射了乳酸林格注射液
We got him on lactated Ringer's running...
病人正在吸十公升的氧气
and the patient is on 10 liters of oxygen.
小心！
Watch it!
那辆救护车在孟斐斯机场一个车库里被发现
The ambulance was found in a parking garage at Memphis Airport.
工作人员死了
The crew was dead.
他还杀了一名游客
He killed a tourist too.
拿了他的衣服和钞票
Got his clothes, cash.
他可能在任何地方
By now he could be anywhere.
-他不会来对付我的　-真的？
- He won't come after me. - Oh, really?
他不会的
He won't.
我不能解释
I can't explain it.
他认为那样做很无礼
He would consider that rude.
都完了，她已经死了
It's over. She's dead.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
莱达说，我们需要捉拿他的资料都在这里，但我不能...
Lecter said everything we need to catch him with is here, only I can't...
莱达医生说了很多话
Dr. Lecter said a lot of things.
雅戴，他在这里的
He's here, Ardelia.
这是莱达的笔迹吗？
Is this Lecter's handwriting?
这样杂乱地分布现场，不是有点极度随意吗？
"Doesn't this random scattering of sites seem desperately random?
像个差劲说谎者的精心策划？汉尼拔・莱达
Like the elaboration of a bad liar? Ta. Hannibal Lecter."
“极度随意”，他是什么意思？
"Desperately random." What does he mean?
可能根本不是随意，是有一个模式的
Not random at all, maybe. Like there's a pattern here.
但并没有模式，不然电脑也会发现
But there's no pattern or the computers would've nailed it.
尸体甚至是不依次序被发现的
They're even found in random order.
不依次序是因为那个被他沈下的女孩
Random because of the one girl. The one he weighted down.
-费迪嘉・拜姆　-对
- Fredrica Bimmel. - Right.
来自俄亥俄州的贝尔维迪尔
From Belvedere, Ohio.
第一个遇害的女孩，尸体是第三个被发现，为什么？
The first girl taken, third body found. Why?
她没有漂浮，他把她沈下去
She didn't drift. He weighted her down.
莱达说的首要原则是什么？
What did Lecter say about the "first principles"?
简易
Simplicity.
这个家伙做什么？他贪图
What does this guy do? He covets.
我们怎样开始贪图的？
How do we first start to covet?
我们贪图见到的东西
We covet what we see.
每天见到的
Every day.
该死，克丽丝
Hot damn, Clarice.
他认识她的
He knew her.
（俄亥俄州贝尔维迪尔市）
贝先生？
Mr. Bimmel?
我是
That's me.
你好，我是克丽丝・史达琳，联邦调查局探员
Hello, I'm Clarice Starling. I'm with the FBI.
贝先生，我想四周看看
I appreciate you letting me take a look around, Mr. Bimmel.
我没有什么新资料给你了
I don't know nothing new to tell you.
警方已经来过很多次
Police been back here so many times already.
费迪坐巴士去芝加哥求职
Fredrica went into Chicago on the bus to see about a job.
她好端端的离开面试
She left the interview okay.
就没有回家
She never come home.
她的卧房是原封不动的
Her bedroom's how she left it.
在楼上
Upstairs.
左边那一间
Door to the left.
他在替自己做女装，用真的女人做
He's making himself a woman suit. Out of real women!
他还懂得缝纫
And he can sew!
他很熟练，他是个裁缝或...
He's very skilled. He's a tailor or a dressmaker or...
-史达琳！　-所以她们都身材肥大
- Starling! - That's why they're big.
他让她们活着，逼使她们挨饿
He keeps them alive so he can starve them...
令她们的皮肤松弛，然后...
loosen their skin and...
史达琳，我们知道他的身份和下落
Starling! We know who and where he is!
我们快到达了
We're on our way right now.
-哪里？　-芝加哥卡柳梅特城
- Where? - Calumet City, edge of Chicago.
我45分钟后会和飞虎队降落
Be on the ground in 45 minutes with HRT.
好消息，但怎么...
That's great news, sir. But how...?
我们把约翰・霍金斯提供的名字，输入已知犯人的档案
We fed the names Johns Hopkins came up with into Known Offenders.
他叫杰米・甘姆，又名约翰・格兰
Subject's name is Jamie Gumb, a.k.a. John Grant.
莱达的描述是正确的，他只是捏造那个名字
Lecter's description was accurate. He just lied about the name.
海关有些关于他的资料
Customs had some paper on him.
两年前他们在洛杉矶机场，查到一个纸箱
They stopped a carton two years ago at LAX.
是一些来自苏里南的活毛虫
Live caterpillars from Suriname.
收件人叫詹米・甘姆
The addressee was a Jame Gumb.
芝加哥离这里只有四百哩，我很快...
Chicago is only 400 miles from here. I'll be there in...
不，没有时间了
No, there's not enough time.
我们要控告他谋杀，不是绑架
We want him for murder, not kidnapping.
在起诉他前，要找出他与费迪嘉・拜姆的关系
Link him to Bimmel before he's indicted.
-你去贝尔维迪尔看有什么发现　-知道，我会尽力的
- See what you can find in Belvedere. - Yes, sir. You bet. I'll do my best.
史达琳
Starling.
没有你我们就找不到他，大家都会记着这点
We wouldn't have found him without you. Nobody will forget that.
尤其是我
Least of all me.
谢谢，长官
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你，葛先生
Thank you very much, Mr. Crawford.
葛先生？
Mr. Crawford?
混蛋，谢谢那些冷饭菜汁
Thanks for the scraps, asshole.
我有更好的主意
I got a better idea.
珍宝，我来招呼你吧
Okay, Precious. Time for a little treat.
珍宝
Precious!
乖乖，来吧
Come on, girl!
来吧，珍宝，乖
Come on, Precious. Come on, Precious.
来吧，珍宝
Come on, Precious.
我有好吃的点心给你
I got a yummy, yummy snack for you.
来吃吧
Come and get it!
珍宝
Precious!
小畜牲，你在上面吗？
Are you up there, you little shit?
快来吃啊，小宝贝
Come and get it, pretty girl.
珍宝
Precious!
求你来吧
Please come. Come on.
来吧，珍宝
Come on, Precious.
你想干我吗？
Would you fuck me?
来吃骨头吧
Come on. Take that bone. Come on.
来吧...
Come on. Come on! Come on!
我想干自己
I'd fuck me.
来吧
Come on.
我想狠狠的干自己
I'd fuck me hard. I'd fuck me so hard.
不
No!
（国家空军防卫队总部）
伊利诺斯州芝加哥市
（莫斯里药房）
当联邦密探很棒吧？要经常出门的吗？
Is that a good job, FBI agent? You get to travel around and stuff?
我是指去比这里好的地方？
I mean, better places than this?
有时要的
Sometimes you do.
我找到这份银行工作时，费迪很替我开心
Freddie was so happy for me when I got this job at the bank.
有烤面包机赠品，整天播着巴尼曼尼罗的歌曲
Toaster giveaways and Barry Manilow on the speakers all day.
她觉得这是份苦差
She thought it was such hot shit.
她知道什么？蠢才
What did she know? Big dummy.
史戴西，费迪可有提过一个叫杰米・甘姆的男人？
Stacy, did Fredrica ever mention a man named Jamie Gumb?
或者詹米・甘姆的人？
Or a Jame Gumb?
-约翰・格兰呢？　-没有
- How about John Grant? - No.
她有没有一个你不认识的朋友？
Would she have had a friend you didn't know?
不可能，如果她有男朋友，我一定会知道
No way. If she had a guy, I'd have known.
缝纫是她的命根
Sewing was her life.
你们有一起工作吗？
Did you ever work together?
我和玛娜茜曾替她做利普曼太太的替工
Me and Pam Malavesi used to help her do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman.
可以把她的地址给我吗？我要跟她谈谈
Can I get Mrs. Lippman's address? I need to talk to her.
（伊利诺斯州卡柳梅特城）
太有劲了
So powerful.
真的漂亮
So beautiful.
珍宝？
Precious?
这里，混蛋！
Down here, you sack of shit!
-把它放在桶里　-不！
- Put her in that bucket. - No!
你立刻给我吊个电话下来
You get me a telephone and lower it down here, now!
乖乖，珍宝？你没事吧？
Oh, poodlie-poo. Precious? Darling, are you all right?
她很痛苦，要找兽医
She's in a lot of pain, mister. She needs a vet.
它下来时折断了腿，它在舐...
She broke her leg on the way down. She's licking...
你别伤害我的狗
Hey! Don't you hurt my dog!
你别逼我伤害你的狗！
Don't you make me hurt your dog!
你不知道什么是痛楚！
You don't know what pain is!
给我拿电话来，否则我杀死它！
Get me that telephone or I'll kill him!
-他妈的！　-你还是给我拿电话来
- Oh, fuck! - You better get me that telephone!
我要动手了
I'm gonna do it, mister!!
我会折断它的颈，我发誓我会的
I'm gonna snap her neck off, I swear to God!
好的，先生，我要做了
All right, mister. I'm doing it!
好的，我来了
Okay, I'm coming.
我们进去
We're going in.
午安，抱歉打扰你
Good afternoon. Sorry to bother you.
我找利普曼太太的家人
I'm looking for Mrs. Lippman's family.
联邦调查局！大家伏下！
FBI! Everybody down!
他们搬走了
Lippmans don't live here anymore.
对不起，先生，我要跟你谈谈
Excuse me, sir. I need to speak with you.
-没有人　-没有人
- Clear! - Clear!
有什么问题呢？
What's the problem, officer?
我正在调查费迪嘉・拜姆的死因
I'm investigating the death of Fredrica Bimmel.
杰克，这里没人
There's no one here, Jack.
克丽丝
Clarice.
阁下是...
Your name is...?
杰克・戈登
Oh, Jack Gordon.
戈登先生，很好
Mr. Gordon. Good.
费迪是利普曼太太的雇员，你认识他吗？
Fredrica worked for Mrs. Lippman. Did you know her?
不认识
No, uh-uh.
等一下
Oh, wait.
她是不是身材肥胖的？
Was she a great big fat person?
是，她很肥胖
Yes, she was a big girl, sir.
对，我可能有...
Yeah, I may have...
不，我在报纸上读到她的新闻
No, I read about her in the newspaper.
利普曼太太有儿子，他或许可以帮忙
Mrs. Lippman had a son. Maybe he could help.
我这里有他的名片
I got his card in here.
你要进来吗？
You want to come in?
-可以吗？　-当然可以
- May I? - Yeah, sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们很快会抓到人吗？
Are you close to catching somebody?
是的
Yes.
或者吧
We may be.
你是不是...
Did you...
在利普曼太太死后搬到这里来？
take over this place after Mrs. Lippman died, is that right?
是的，我两年前买了这间屋
Yeah, I bought this house two years ago.
她有没有留下任何记录，业务记录...
Did she leave any records, any business records...
税单，雇员名单之类？
tax forms, lists of employees?
没有，完全没有
No, nothing like that at all.
联邦调查局可有什么发现？
Say, has the FBI learned something?
这里的警方看来毫无头绪
The police around here don't seem to have the first clue.
你们有没有容貌，指纹之类的线索？
Have you got, like, a description, fingerprints, anything like that?
没有
No.
我们没有
No, we don't.
是这个电话号码了
Here's that number.
很好
Very good, Mr. Gordon.
可否借用你的电话？
May I use your phone, please?
当然可以
Sure you can use my phone.
别动！
Freeze!
把双手放在头上，转过来，张开腿
Put your hands over your head and turn around. Spread your legs.
张开腿
Spread your legs!
把双手放在...
Put your hands in the back...
别动！
Freeze!
喂！
Hey!
你在吗？
Are you there?
我在下面...
I'm down here! I'm down here!
凯瑟琳・马丁？
Catherine Martin?
是！
Yes!
联邦调查局
FBI.
你安全了
You're safe.
安全个屁！快救我出去
Safe, shit! Get me out of here!
你没事的，他在哪里？
You're all right. Where is he?
我怎么知道？快救我出去！
How the fuck should I know? Just get me out of here!
凯瑟琳，你静一点，叫那只狗别吵
Catherine, you've gotta be quiet! Now, shut that dog up!
快救我出去！
Just get me out of here!
我的天
Oh, my God.
凯瑟琳，我会救你的，但你听着
Catherine, I'm gonna get you out. But right now, you listen to me.
我要离开一会，很快回来
I've gotta leave. I'll be right back
不，不要丢下我，你这个婊子，别走！
No! Don't you leave me here, you fucking bitch! No!
不要丢下我！
Don't you leave me here!
这个家伙是疯的！
This guy is fucking crazy!
等一下，我要离开这里
Wait! I gotta get out of here!
求求你！
Please!
凯瑟琳！其他的探员会很快到达的
Catherine! The other officers will be here any minute now.
不要走！求求你
Wait! Don't go! Please!
别吵！
Quiet!
天啊...
Oh, God! Oh, God!
（恐怖）
（比尔剥下第五个人的皮）
-你没事吧？　-小事，不要紧，我没事
- You okay? - Gunpowder. It's nothing, I'm okay.
史达琳探员，你怎么追查到水牛比尔在这里的？
Agent Starling, how did you track Buffalo Bill here?
（司法部联邦调查局）
克丽丝・史达琳
Clarice M. Starling.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
昂利・史蒂文
Ernest W. Stevens.
特种探员克丽丝・史达琳！
Special Agent Starling!
-特种探员麦普　-有电话找你
- Special Agent Mapp. - Phone call.
谢谢，失陪
Thank you. Excuse me.
史达琳
Starling.
替我们拍照好吗？
Pilch, could you take our picture?
好的
Sure.
我只想说声恭喜
I just wanted to say congratulations.
我不擅应酬，所以我要走了
I'm no good at this kind of thing, so I'm gonna duck out of here.
好的
Okay. Sure.
谢谢，葛先生
Thank you, Mr. Crawford.
令尊今天定会很骄傲
Your father would've been proud today.
别忘了接听电话
Don't forget your phone call.
史达琳
Starling.
克丽丝...
Well, Clarice...
那些羔羊停止尖叫了吗？
have the lambs stopped screaming?
莱达医生？
Dr. Lecter?
不必追踪这个电话，我不会讲太久
Don't bother with a trace. I won't be on long enough.
莱达医生，你在哪里？
Where are you, Dr. Lecter?
我不打算找你了
I have no plans to call on you.
有了你，这个世界更加有趣
The world's more interesting with you in it.
你保重，日后报答我吧
So you take care now to extend me the same courtesy.
我不能作那个承诺的
You know I can't make that promise.
但愿我们可以多聊一会
I do wish we could chat longer...
但我找了个老朋友吃晚饭
but I'm having an old friend for dinner.
再见
Bye.
莱达医生！
Dr. Lecter!
莱达医生
Dr. Lecter.
莱达医生？
Dr. Lecter?
抱歉，对不起
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
保安系统安排了吗？
The security system's set up?
-我们有严密保安的　-谢谢
- We have the big shot security. - I appreciate it.